It's Another 'Four Daughters' Hit! And they're gayer than
ever, sweeter than ever, better than ever before!
Daughters Courageous is a drama, romance film directed by Michael Curtiz.
Nan Masters, a single mother living with her four marriageable
daughters, plans to marry Sam Sloane, businessman.
Out of the blue her first husband Jim returns after
deserting the family 20 years earlier.
The worldly wanderer Jim gets a cool family reception at first but his warm
personality gradually wins the affections of his four daughters.
In fact, youngest daughter Buff, who has her eye on a maverick of her own in Gabriel
Lopez, is pleased when Jim grants his stamp of approval on her relationship.
Buff plans to elope with Gabriel on her mother's wedding day,
but 'unpredictable' is Gabriel's middle name.
Gabriel Lopez, played by John Garfield.
Jim Masters, played by Claude Rains.
John S. 'Johnny' Heming, played by Jeffrey Lynn.
Nancy 'Nan' Masters, played by Fay Bainter.
Samuel 'Sam' Sloane, played by Donald Crisp.
Penny, the Housekeeper, played by May Robson.
Daughters Courageous is a 1939 American drama film starring John Garfield, Claude Rains,
Jeffrey Lynn and featuring the Lane Sisters: Lola, Rosemary and Priscilla.
Based on the play Fly Away Home by Dorothy Bennett and Irving
White, the film was directed by Michael Curtiz.
It was released by Warner Bros.
on June 23, 1939.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, ex husband,
family relationships, wedding, single mother.
The tone is emotional.